Stamo Papadaki Papers, 1922-1990 (bulk 1930-1970): Finding Aid C0845
Manuscripts Division
Stamo Papadaki Papers
1922-1990
1930-1970
Manuscripts Division
Mouseio Synchronēs Technēs (Andros Island, Greece).
Papadaki, Stamo.
C0845
36 boxes
24 items
Consists of papers of architect, poet, editor, and author Stamo Papadaki. Included is correspondence (1922-1990) with many architects from the United States, Europe, Greece, and Brazil, as well as correspondence with organizations, artists, friends, and family. Also included are various manuscripts, articles, blueprints and plans, printed matter, photographs, and subject files on Papadaki's works.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of papers of Papadaki. Included is correspondence (1922-1990) with many architects from the United States, Europe, Greece, and Brazil, such as Jorge Amado, Charles S. Ascher, Leonidas Cheferrino, Serge Chermayeff, Lucio Costa, Marcel Gautherot, Matila Ghyka, Siegfried Giedion, Walter Gropius, Jean Helion, Le Corbusier (Charles Edouard Jeanneret), Lazlo Moholy-Nagy, Oscar Niemeyer, Amedee Ozenfant, Eugene C. Petit, Alberto Sartoris, Jose Sert, and Frank Lloyd Wright. There is also correspondence with organizations, artists, friends, and family, including the Architectural Forum, Alexander Calder, John Dale, Macmillan Company, the Museum of Modern Art (N.Y.), CIAM, Michales Tompros, and Henry Yannilos, and a lengthy correspondence (1939-1979) with his sisters, Maria and Photeine, in Greece.
Works include manuscripts and photographs for his book Le Corbusier, Architect, Painter, Writer, an unpublished work entitled The Compass and the Unicorn: Modulations of the Inhabited Space (circa 1962), various articles, book reviews, and two compilations of poetry, "Les Jeux et Les Jours" and "De Trebizonde a Metaponte et au Dela" (1972).
Subject files contain correspondence, photographs, articles, notes, drawings, and printed matter relating to the development of Brasilia, his work on various projects for the CIAM, and plans for a Le Corbusier exhibition; drawings, notes, and manuscripts of his research with Le Corbusier and Le Corbusier's own writings for Le Modular (1954), a system of harmonious measurement for architects and mechanics (the papers also include an original, hand-drawn, colored, and signed "modulor" tape by Le Corbusier); covers and layouts for the magazines Plus and Progressive Architecture; plans and articles on prefabricated houses and mountain shelters; and many plans, blueprints, drawings, elevations, and photographs for other architectural projects, including the New York World's Fair pavilion, the New York International Airport, a seaside villa near Athens, office buildings on Park Avenue, exhibitions for IBEC and UNESCO, designs and photographs (circa 1981) for the Museum of Modern Art on Andros Island, Greece, and houses and commercial buildings in Greece, Brazil, and the United States.
Also present are blueprints and plans (1940s) for Papadaki's home in Washington, Connecticut, original drawings and works of abstract art, furniture designs by Papadaki and Le Corbusier, photographs of Papadaki and Le Corbusier, including a photograph of Le Corbusier with Albert Einstein, diplomas and award certificates, printed matter, including copies of the Brazilian newspaper Para Todos and publications in Greek, and articles or designs of other people such as Siegfried Giedion, Fernand Leger, Vladimir Bodiansky, Alberto Sartoris, and Andre Wogenscky.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research use.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Audrey Papadaki.
Appraisal
No appraisal information is available.
Papadaki, Stamo.
Biographical / Historical
Architect Stamo Papadaki was born in Athens, Greece, in 1906. He attended Athens Polytechnic and then moved to France, where he studied under Auguste Perret and others, and received his Diplome d'Architecte et d'Urbaniste in 1929. In 1935 Papadaki went to New York as the designer for American Houses, Inc., which specialized in prefabricated houses. His clients included the French government, UNESCO, and the New York Port Authority, for which he served as planner for the Idlewild (now John F. Kennedy) Airport. He also won a design competition for a pavilion for the New York World's Fair (1939-1940), served (1938-1946) on the Architectural Committee of the Museum of Modern Art (N.Y.), was an active member of CIAM (International Congress of Modern Art), and was one of the three foreign judges of the planning competition (1957) for the new Brazilian capital of Brasilia. In addition to his practice as an architect Papadaki also worked as art editor (1948-1960) for the Architectural Forum, was Professor of Architecture and Design (1948-1960) at Brooklyn College of the City University of New York, was editor of the publications Plus and Progressive Architecture, wrote two books on the Brazilian architect Oscar Niemeyer, edited Le Corbusier, Architect, Painter, Writer (1948), and authored many articles, book reviews, and works of poetry.
Architecture -- Designs and plans -- Brazil -- 20th century.; Architecture -- Designs and plans -- Greece -- 20th century.; Architecture -- Designs and plans -- United States -- 20th century.; Architecture, Domestic -- Greece -- 20th century.; Architecture, Domestic -- United States -- 20th century.; Architecture, Modern -- 20th century -- Brazil.; Architecture, Modern -- 20th century -- Greece.; Architecture, Modern -- 20th century -- United States.; Furniture design -- 20th century.; Modular coordination (Architecture).; Prefabricated houses.; Public architecture -- Brazil -- 20th century.; Seaside architecture -- Greece -- 20th century.; Brasília (Brazil) -- Design.; John F. Kennedy Interantional Airport (N.Y.).; New York International Airport.; Architectural drawings.; Blueprints.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Greek American architects -- 20th century.; Papadaki family; Mouseio Synchronēs Technēs (Andros Island, Greece).; Le Corbusier, 1887-1965; Niemeyer, Oscar, 1907-2012; Papadaki, Maria
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1920-1992; 4 boxes; 20 items
  Scope and Contents
  The count of letters in parentheses includes letters to Papadaki and carbons of his replies when they occur.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - ac (Revue internationale d'amiante-ciment letters), 1957; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agras, Tellos, 1920s; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albini, Franco, 1950; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aloi, Roberto, 1933-1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amado, Jorge, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Para Todos
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1964; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Defense, Harvard Group, 1943-1944; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Institute, 1936; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Red Cross, New York Chapter, 1942; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Society of Planners and Architects, 1944-1946; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Antoniades, Anthony C, 1985; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Architects Committee of the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc, 1945-1946; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Architecture in Greece, 1990; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Architectural Association, 1939; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Architectural Design, 1950; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Architectural Forum, 1944-1966; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Architectural Record, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Architectural Review, 1944-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Architecture-Forms-Functions, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ascher, Charles S, 1958-1975; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Association des Artistes et Gens de Lettres Hellènes de Paris, 1927; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Association Internationale des Critiques D'Art, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aujame, R, 1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bacon, Mardges, 1992; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
    re: Le Corbusier
  - Bardi, P. M, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bâtir: Revue Mensuelle D'Architecture, 1933-1938; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bauwelt, 1931; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bayer, Herbert, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bayer, Joella, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bergen, Emiel, 1956-1958; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bichet, Georges, 1978-1986; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bistis, A. M, 1944; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bittencourt, Niomar M. S, 1957-1958; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Higher Education: New York, 1950-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bodiansky, Vladimir, 1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1957; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bouchard, Thomas & Diane, 1966-1973; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bouxin, André, 1946-1966; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brash, Edward, 1964; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brasilia, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Pinheiro, Niemeyer, Cheferrino & subject series
  - Brentano's, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Breton, Michel, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brigandin, Roger, 1947; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brown's Hotel, 1947; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Burle Marx, W, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Calas, Nicolas, 1945-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Calder, Nanette, 1950; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Calder, Sandy [Alexander], 1972; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Canaday, John, 1961-1969; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carlu, Jean, 1957; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1950; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carpenter Center for the Visual Arts, 1965; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carroll, Edwin W, 1960; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Casa Editrice, 1963; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Charles Hardy, Inc., dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Dale, John D.
  - Cheferrino, Leonidas V, 1956; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chermayeff, Serge, 1947-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cheronis, Nicholas & Irene, 1955-1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chimicles, George N, 1951; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Christ-Janer, Albert, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coates, Wells, 1934-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Columbia University, 1957-1965; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Commission on Community Interrelations of the American Jewish, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Congress, 1945; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Connecticut Light & Power Co, 1972; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Costa, Lucio, 1960; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Costi, 1964-1968; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Daedalus, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dale, John D, 1947-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Damaz, Paul, 1962-1964; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dannilos, Henry, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Defenbacher, D. S, 1945; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dinsmore, William B, 1934; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Doumanēs, Orestēs, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Durisol, Inc., dates not examined; 1 item
  - Duthuit, Georges, Claude & Marguerite Claude, 1960-1982; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Editions Saint-Germain-Des-Prés, 1972; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Emery, Erica, 1980; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Emery, P-A, 1936-1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Empeirikos, Andreas, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Entwistle, Clive, 1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fenzy, Fernand, 1936; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Forbat, Fred, 1933; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - French, Leigh, Jr, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gabo, Miriam, 1939; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gandolfi, Vittorio, 1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gardella, Ignazio, 1938; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gautherot, Marcel, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - George Braziller, Inc, 1960-1965; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ghyka, Matila, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
    See also: Dale, John
  - Giacumacatos, Andreas, 1982-1985; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gideonse, Harry D. [Brooklyn College], 1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Giedion, Siegfried, 1945-1971; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ginsberg, Jean & Mae, 1938-1977; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Goldstone, Jeannette & John, 1973; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Goodwin, Philip, 1956; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Greek Archdiocese of North and South America, 1959-1963; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Greene, Elizabeth de Courcy, 1953; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gropius, Walter & Mrs, 1944-1972; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Guenar, John R., Major, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Guevrekian, Gabriel, 1948-1950; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Guffey, Dione M, 1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gutmann, Robert, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gutwirth, Charles, 1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Hablemos, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hanmer, Lee F, 1937; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hanning, G, 1947; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Harriman, William Averell, Mrs, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Harrison, Wallace K, 1938-1958; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc, 1964-1965; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Hélion, Jean, 1939-1983; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Henrot, Paul, 1972; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Hilberseimer, Hans, 1945; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Hilberseimer, Ludwig, 1945; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Holden, Arthur C, 1936; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Holford, William, Sir, 1961; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Holland, Hilda, 1946; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Holtzman, Harry, 1951-1969; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Horizon, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hotel D'Angleterre, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hudnut, Joseph, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: American Society of Planners and Architects
  - Institute of Design, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Chermayeff, Moholy-Nagy & Paepcke
  - International Assoc. of Art Critics, Congress, Brazil, 1959; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ionnou, Euangelos, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Agras, Tellos
  - J. J. Little & Ives Co., Inc, 1961-1963; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Jeanneret, C.?, undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Jeanneret, Charles Edouard, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Le Corbusier
  - Jeanneret, L., Mme, 1926; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Jouven, Georges, 1980; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Kapre, B. S, 1962; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Kitsikis, Anthony, 1947-1964; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Knoll Associates, Inc, 1949; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Koch, Alexander, 1954-1955; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Kocher, [Alfred Lawrence], undated; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - [Koyanagis?], 1937; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Labo, Mario, 1934-1936; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - La Grassa, Francesco, 1948; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Landgren, Marchal E, 1962-1966; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Le Corbusier, 1933-1961; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 3)
    See also: Macmillan; Dale
  - Le Corbusier, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Misc. corresp. re: "Modulor"
  - Leclercq, Ovide, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lennox, Richard K, 1960; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, 1945; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - London Magazine, 1970; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lubetkin, Berthold, 1938-1944; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lydakes, Stelios, 1960; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Macmillan Company, 1947-1954; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 8)
    re: Le Corbusier book
  - Marchesscan, Monsieur, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mariacher, Bruno, 1967-1969; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - MARS Group, 1938-1945; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Martin, Jean-Claude, 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1961; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Matibag, Edmar A, 1959; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Matter, Herbert & Mercedes, 1945; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - McLaughlin, Robert, 1955-1957; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Merkelbach, Ben, 1937; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Michel, Jacques, 1958; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miës van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1932; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mindlin, Henrique E, 1958; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mirador, 1956; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Módulo, 1955-1959; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 12)
    See also: Cheferrino, Niemeyer, Queiroz
  - Moholy-Nagy, Lazlo & Sibyl, 1933-1948; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Moretti, Bruno, 1936; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Museum of Modern Art: New York, 1938-1966; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1943; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - National Science Foundation, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Neurath, Otto, 1937-1940; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Neutra, Richard J, 1951; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - New Haven Railroad, 1957; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - New York University, 1958; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nicholson, Bill, 1940; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Nicolopoulos, Paul, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Niemeyer, Oscar, 1949-1954; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Niemeyer, Oscar, 1955-1966; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Niemeyer, Oscar, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 19)
    undated & misc. material
  - Nitzchke, Oscar, 1953-1954; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nivola, Costantino, 1956; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Oeconomou, Elie Th, 1945; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Olgyay, Aladar, 1955; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Orion & Global Chartering Co, 1981; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ozenfant, Amédée, 1939-1960; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Paepcke, Walter P, 1946; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pantheon Books, Inc, 1957; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Papadaki, Audrey [wife], 1974; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Papadaki, Johanna (Jeanne) [mother], 1935-1938; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Papadaki, Johanna (Jeanne) [mother], 1939-1952; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Papadaki, Maria & Photeine [sisters], 1939-1960; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Papadaki, Maria & Photeine [sisters], 1961-1971; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Papadaki, Maria & Photeine [sisters], 1972-1979; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Para Todos, 1957-1959; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Park, Brock & Helen, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pasadena Playhouse, 1960; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Paulhan, Jean, 1956; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pencil Points, 1945; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Petit, Eugène Claudius, 1946-1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Petroleum Engineer Publishing Co, 1960; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pevsner, Antoine, 1938; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pinheiro, Israel, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pontabry, Robert, 1951-1959; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Princeton University, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: McLaughlin, Robert
  - Pritchard, J. C, 1947; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Progressive Architecture, 1962; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Prokopiou, Angelos, 1961-1962; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Queiroz, Mauricio Vinhas de, 1960-1962; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Rading, Adolf, 1932; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Rail Travel Credit Agency, 1971; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Raimond, Emil, 1957; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Raymond, Antonin, 1937; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Reinhardt, Ad, 1955; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Reinhold Publishing Corporation, 1948-1967; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - La Revue Européenne, 1928; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Roberts, A. Leonard, 1948; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rodis, T, 1940s; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rogers, Ernesto N, 1948-1954; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rosenfield, Isadore, 1947; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roth, Alfred, 1940s; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roucas, Laz, 1946; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roux, [Lalquelize Lighot?], 1961-1967; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roux-Spitz, Michel, 1929; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Royal Greek Embassy Information Service, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Royal Institute of British Architects, 1935-1936; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Russell, Alfred, 1963; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Saldanha, Firmino, 1959; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Sartoris, Alberto, 1938-1962; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Schmidt, F.?, 1949; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Schniewind, Carl O, 1945; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Seligmann, Kurt, 1944-1957; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Sert, José Luis, 1933-1973; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
    See also: Subject Series: CIAM
  - Seyrig, Henri, 1961; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Shand, P. Morton, 1933-1944; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sicard, M, 1964; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Siegel, Ing. Curt, 1959-1960; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Simeoforidis, Georgios, 1986; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Simons, Jacques R, 1944; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Sive, André, 1946-1958; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Skaling, Percy E, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Smith College Museum of Art, 1948; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - SNAG Club, 1981; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Sobrinho, Francisco Matarazzo, 1952; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Soby, James Thrall, 1947; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Société des Architectes Diplomés, 1934-1937; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sofianopoulos, John, 1945; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Spanudis, Th, undated; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Stasinopoulos, Michael, 1922-1924; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Stonorov, Oscar, 1945; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Strick, Joseph, 1961; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav, 1951; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Svaz Architektu CSR, 1960; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Sweeney, James Johnson, 1945-1962; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Syrkus, Helena, 1973; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Tanguy, Yves, circa 1950; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Thomas, M. Hartland, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tompros, Michalēs [cousin], 1933-1972; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tournakis, Sofia, 1952; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tzakone, Giorgos, 1992; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - UNESCO, 1953; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - United Nations, 1944-1953; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Van Eesteren, C, 1937; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Van Gelderen, W, 1937; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Varèse, Edgard, 1942-1965; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vasconcellos, Dora Alencar de, 1956-1957; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vitsaris, Basil, undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Walters, Raymond, Jr, 1951; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Weisman, Barbara J, 1955; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Weissberger, Jose A, undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wiener, Paul, 1956-1961; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wight, Frederick S, 1948; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Amancio, 1940s; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Wolff, Kurt, dates not examined; 1 item
    See: Pantheon Books
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1930-1935; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Wyckoff, Jane Brown, undated; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Yale University, 1940; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Yannilos, Henry [cousin], 1937-1972; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Yorke, F. R. S, 1944; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Zervos, Christian, 1944-1968; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Zuck, Klaus R, 1962; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 14)